# **Andrew Whiting**

3027 Knolls End Dr. #2 ♦ Fort Collins, CO 80526 ♦ 240-760-9543 ♦ whiting49@gmail.com ♦ www.abwhiting.com

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic software dev. with 2.5 years of experience in Python for data science/analytics and 1.5 years of experience in full-stack software engineering. Expert in Python for backend development, full-stack development, scripting, data wrangling, and data analysis. Competent in both front and backend application development. Passionate and rapid learner and with an educational and professional background in structured finance, business strategy, and international dev.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages	Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS	Frameworks	Flask, Django, Vue.JS, Kivy, KivyMD
DB	SQLite3, Google Firebase, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLAlchemy	IDEs and Tools	Git CLI, Jupyter Notebook, iPython, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, Linode
Stat. Analysis	Signif. testing & design, Bayesian inference	Finance Modeling	CapEx, ARIMA, time series, exp. smoothing
Data Prep.	Cleaning, factorization, regex, text processing	Data Visualization	Grammar of graphics, small multiples
Key Libraries	PyTest, Numpy, Pandas, Keras, MatPlotLib, Plotly, Beautiful Soup, Requests, CV2	Methodologies	Functional programming, OOP, Agile, Unit testing, Test-driven development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Freelance Python Developer**

November 2021 - present

- Coordinated with clients to identify and refine project requirements
- Developed bespoke python script to automate client onboarding processes
- Developed flight tracking web app with full database integration input validation
- Developed full-featured cross-platform mobile application to track workouts

Python, Bash, Google People, Pandas, smptlib Python, Flask, REST, SQLite3, SQLAlchemy, Vue.js, JS, bs4, Linode Python, Kivy, KivyMD, MatPlotLib, Google Firebase

### **Director of Finance, Investment Management, and Data Analytics**

**Africa Vision Partners** 

Washington, DC July 2021 to Present

Python, Dash, Plotly

Python, Excel, VBA

- Design, develop, implement, and maintain data dashboard for KPIs and key data visualization
- Perform data wrangling, modeling, and analysis to drive executive strategic decision making
- Perform strategic and financial planning for the development of two smart cities in Greater Port Harcourt, Nigeria and Kisii, Kenya valued at USD 1.3B
- Built and maintaining 3-statement financial models for large structured-finance projects including a USD 110M hospital, USD 40M power plant, and 35M hotel and conference center

Excel, VBA

# **Director of International Projects**

Redwood Global

June 2017 to July 2021

Washington, DC

- Perform data wrangling, modeling, and analysis to drive executive strategic decision making
   Python, Excel, VBA
- Managed a team of 15 consultants for a multi-billion-dollar company analyzing, modeling, and structuring deals across a variety of industries including infrastructure, renewables, aviation, and mining
- Performed financial modeling and analysis of dozens of large infrastructure projects ranging from USD 25M to USD 3B located through Africa and the Middle East
- Negotiated contracts and partnership/JV agreements and developed business strategy at the managing director level with fortune 500 companies and senior politicians both domestic and foreign

## **EDUCATION**

Johns Hopkins University: Master of Arts in International Finance and International Political Economy

Brigham Young University: Bachelor of Arts in Middle East Studies and Arabic

Au

May 2017 August 2014

**Relevant Online Coursework:** Harvard: CS50, Udemy: Design Patterns in Python, the Python Mega Course, the Complete Data Structures and Algorithms Course in Python

Spoken Languages: English (native), Arabic (advanced), Russian (advanced), Spanish (advanced)